A thing that happens in many organizations is we want to be uniform in our project management approach
that we want all projects to have the same types of processes the same terminology the same expectations
with stakeholders.
So we create an organizational project management so organizational project management is what we're
talking about here.
And how does this mesh with the strategy of the organization.
So OPM organizational project management sometimes you might see this as organizational project management
Maturity Model or OPM 3.
But for our exam we just notice organizational project management and that it's a way to coordinate
manage control programs and projects so that our portfolio of all of our investments are managed in
a uniform consistent effort.
What we don't want is Bob over here is using lean and Sallys using adaptive or ad Jayal and I'm using
predictive and we all have different forms that approaches in a way to do the project because there's
lots of different ways to manage a project and all of those ways are fine all those ways are good.
However that creates confusion for stakeholders and customers because when they work with Bob they do
it one way and with Sallee they have a different approach.
With me we have a different approach.
So it just creates a lot of ruckus in our project rather than being uniform across all of us making
a decision at an executive level with OPM on how we're going to manage projects because we want to consistently
deliver better projects.
And if we all take the same approach and we tailor OK but we have a same approach it's going to make
it better for everyone in the organization.
Let's take a look at some facts about OPM first goal of OPM.
If you want to think about goals and tactics.
Why are we doing projects.
How does this help us deliver business value.
How does that help our organizational goals.
So we want to think about the goals and the tactics.
Then we go into value decisions.
So value decisions are talking about business value.
How does this make our business more valuable.
How does this create value for our stakeholders and by creating a uniform approach.
How does that improve upon business value and then results delivery which approach gets work done most
effectively and efficiently profit Vau you return on investment.
So what about results delivery and then this the fourth step is based on those results.
How do we see business value how do we measure that.
What's the realization of what we've created.
So we start very high we think about goals and tactics and strategy and then we think about value decisions
which should we invest in.
So portfolio management event results delivery that those projects follow a uniform approach and they
are creating value so that we see the business value realization.
So the return on investment.
The improvement in our market share happier stakeholders.
So what's the business value realization and important concept here as well as projects and strategic
planning.
Any organization.
Well not any but most organizations follow this trying go here of executives functional management and
operations operations is the broadest we're most people are in our organization functional managements
kind of idea of middle management as you're stuck in the middle between operations and the executives
at the top.
So the closer you get to the top the fewer people they are in the population.
So at the executive level when it comes to projects or OPM they're thinking why why do we want to do
this project.
How does this support the vision of our company how does it move us closer to the vision.
How does this support our mission as an organization.
What about our goals for the year or the five year.
So how does it support the goals.
So executives want to know why should we do this project functional management's thinking about what
what's the mechanics of the project that will support the strategy and the tactics of the organization.
So how does this help us achieve the layer above.
How does this help us achieve the vision.
We need strategy and tactics to achieve the vision or the goals of the mission so functional management
is looking at what and in lines of business and core functions the operations the day to day they're
thinking about how how can we implement this project to achieve the watt or the Y.
So projects.
All three of those levels that we start off very broad in the charter with why are we doing this.
And then we get into the scope of planning we think about what what are we doing exactly making decisions
and what and then the how is where we work with our project team its subject matter experts.
If we think about how will we accomplish the project to support those strategies which the strategies
should support the vision the mission and the goals of the project.
Finally organizations and project management just some things that we want to address here that may
affect the remainder of the course that might affect your exam.
First off we want to talk about project based organizations project based organizations and entities
that their income is generated by doing projects for others.
So a construction company.
Each house they build is a project or I.T. integrator or a software development company that everything
they do is a project.
So they need a very uniform approach to project management because everything they do is a project they
want a uniform approach so they can measure performance measure profitability measure business value
we also ought to talk about project management and organizational governance.
We'll see more about governance throughout the course but governance are like the rules the framework
the structure of how we operate.
So what are we allowed to do.
So our projects have to be meshed with organizational governance that we just can't go off on our own
and make up our own rules.
We have to follow the governance of the organization.
Now that organization could also be within the program.
So we have a program governance that we follow projects and organizational strategy have to be in sync
with each other that we don't get to launch projects that don't support our strategy.
If our strategy is to be a construction company we're building houses we probably don't need a project
where we're going to start creating a service to create Web sites that that really doesn't sync with
what we're doing as a business.
We may have had excellent web site designer but it doesn't really support our goal and vision.
And you know frankly something this is what I've wrestled with in my company you know my company's instructing
dot com and I offer these types of training.
Well we have become efficient at editing these videos and publishing videos and so on.
But I can only teach so many videos right there's only so many things that I know about.
So it's like well we've got some really good video editors but I can't keep them busy all the time.
So should we start other services where we offer video editing.
It's not really the goal and the vision of my organization of teaching project management of the teaching
adult education.
So that doesn't really fit with the with the strategy of the organization.
So any project that we create has to support the strategy but also we have to consider the culture if
we are in a really big company a really big bank.
There's a culture in a way that people interact with each other that's probably different if we're in
a small startup with just you know a dozen or you know a hundred people is going to be a different culture
in that type of industry.
Definitely from banking to you know a dot.com company or from banking to an insurance company even so
there's a different culture.
And we also have culture in different parts of the world that affects how we do the work.
So there's a different culture in New York versus in Tampa Florida or Chicago or in Sydney Australia
or over there in Antwerp in Belgium or Paris so all there's local cultures that affect how you do the
work and how you operate in that organization.
All right all important stuff.
We're moving forward.
I'll see you in the next lecture.